Universal Negro Improvement Association records, 1921-1989
Emory University
- Administrative records, 1926-1987, Series 2; Boxes 14-18
  - Division records, 1926-1977, Subseries 2.2; Boxes 17-18
    - Cincinnati, Ohio (Division No. 345a), monthly report of local divisions, 1955-1962 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Cincinnati, Ohio (Division No. 345a), newsletter, etc. (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Cleveland, Ohio (Division No. 413), minutes, 1957, 1972 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Cleveland, Ohio (Division No. 413), monthly report of local divisions, 1958-1961 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Cleveland, Ohio (Division No. 413), ordinance, 1926 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Cleveland, Ohio (Division No. 413), proclamation UNIA Day, 1977 (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Columbus, Ohio (Division No. 328), monthly report of local divisions, 1957 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Dayton, Ohio (Division No. 371), monthly report of local divisions, 1952-1958 (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Detroit, Michigan (Division No. 407), minutes, 1974 (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - Detroit, Michigan (Division No. 407), monthly report of local divisions, 1956-1958 (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - Michigan (Universal African Nationalists, Division No. 135), monthly report of local divisions, 1981 (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - New Orleans, Louisiana (Division No. 400), articles of incorporation, 1954 (Box 17, Folder 21)
    - New Orleans, Louisiana (Division No. 400), minutes, 1954, 1956, 1960 (Box 17, Folder 22)
    - New Orleans, Louisiana (Division No. 400), monthly report of local divisions, 1954-1957 (Box 17, Folder 23)
    - New Orleans, Louisiana (Gentilly Division No. 402), records, 1960-1961 (Box 17, Folder 24)
    - New Orleans, Louisiana (Gentilly Division No. 402), monthly report of local divisions, 1955-1957 (Box 17, Folder 25)
    - New York, New York (Central Division), minutes, 1942 (Box 17, Folder 26)
    - New York, New York (Central Division), monthly report of local divisions, 1938 (Box 17, Folder 27)
    - New York, New York (Division No. 340), minutes, 1938 (Box 17, Folder 28)
    - New York, New York (Division No. 340), monthly report of local divisions, 1938 (Box 17, Folder 29)
    - New York, New York (Division No. 340), oath of the Universal African League, no date (Box 17, Folder 30)
    - Ohio, members and divisions (Box 17, Folder 31)
    - Ohio State Conference (Cleveland, Ohio), minutes, 1941 (Box 17, Folder 32)
    - Philadelphia, Pennsylvania (Division No. 121), Emergency African Redemption Committee (Division 121), rules, no date (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Philadelphia, Pennsylvania (Division No. 121), bylaws, no date (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Philadelphia, Pennsylvania (Division No. 121), fire insurance policy, 1949 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Philadelphia, Pennsylvania (Division No. 121), members, no date (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Philadelphia, Pennsylvania (Division No. 121), minutes, 1952-1953 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Philadelphia, Pennsylvania (Division No. 121), minutes, 1954-1956 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Philadelphia, Pennsylvania (Division No. 121), minutes, 1958-1960 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Philadelphia, Pennsylvania (Division No. 121), miscellaneous (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Philadelphia, Pennsylvania (Division No. 121), monthly report of local divisions, 1952-1956 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Philadelphia, Pennsylvania (Division No. 121), monthly report of local divisions, 1957-1963 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Philadelphia, Pennsylvania (Division No. 121), officers, 1962 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Philadelphia, Pennsylvania (Division No. 121), resolutions, 1940-1943 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Philadelphia, Pennsylvania (Division No. 121), vote on 1609 Columbia Avenue (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Raleigh, North Carolina, articles of incorporation, 1974 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - International
    - Canada: Montreal Division, members, no date (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Costa Rica: Limón (Division 300), members, no date (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Costa Rica: Limón (Division 300), minutes, 1941 (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Cuba: Havana (Division 203), affidavit, 1953 (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - Jamaica: multiple Divisions, minutes, 1956-1961 (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - Jamaica: Cockburne (Division 425), minutes, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 20)
    - Jamaica: Kingston, (Division No. 398), monthly report of local divisions, 1955-1957 (Box 18, Folder 21)
    - Jamaica: Kingston (Harmony Division), resolution, 1957 (Box 18, Folder 22)
    - Jamaica: Kingston (Progressive Division 1), member (Box 18, Folder 23)
    - Jamaica: Kingston, (Rollington Town Division), records, 1955-1957 (Box 18, Folder 24)
    - Jamaica: Kingston, (Western Star Division), monthly report of local divisions, 1957 (Box 18, Folder 25)
    - Jamaica: Whitfield Town (United African Community Division), monthly report of local divisions, 1957 (Box 18, Folder 26)
    - Liberia: Organization of divisions (Box 18, Folder 27)
    - Liberia: Secret message codes (Box 18, Folder 28)
    - Nova Scotia: Glace Bay (Division No. 303), monthly report of local divisions, 1958 (Box 18, Folder 29)
    - Panama, Republic of Panama (Division No. 244), reports, no date (Box 18, Folder 30)
    - South Africa: Ludaka (Division No. 2), minutes, 1953 (Box 18, Folder 31)
    - [Location unknown] (Box 18, Folder 32)
- Photographs, 1925-1978, Series 3; Box 19
  The series consists of photographs relating to the UNIA, in the United States, Africa and the Caribbean Islands. There are photographs of individuals associated with the UNIA, as well images of the 1929 and 1955 UNIA conventions, and locations and events in Ghana, Liberia, Jamaica, and the Dominican Republic.
  Arranged by subject matter.
  - Individuals
  - Alleyne, J., Captain and Chief of the 1st N.Y. African Legion, no date [photographer: Morais Photo Studio, Kingston, Jamaica] (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Asiko, Harriet Ruth and Phyllis Violet Oyieza (daughters of Mr. And Mrs. Obina) (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Brantley, James, no date (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Dinzey, Israel [in Universal African Legion uniform], no date (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Garvey, Amy Ashwood, no date (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Garvey, Amy Jacques, Jamaica Minister Edward Seaga, Eustace Whyte and Martin Luther King, Jr., at Marcus Garvey Shrine, June 1965 [photographer: Gleaner Photo, Kingston, Jamaica] (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Harvey, Thomas W., with Georgina Thornton and Arnold Lemuel Crawford, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, circa 1972 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Howard, Humbert, no date (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Kennedy, Edna M., no date (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Liberty Gospel Singing Chorus, Mrs. Susie Griffin (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Nkrumah, Kwame, no date (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Prescott, Ruth Peart (Marcus Garvey's niece), no date (Box 19, Folder 41)
  - Sherrill, Joya, no date [photographers: Murray Korman and James J. Kriegsmann] (7 photos) (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Sherrill, William L., no date (4 photos) [Includes photograph of (left to right) William Sherrill, Harold Bledsoe, Thomas Drum, William L. Dawson, Emmett Cunningham, and Joseph A. Craigen, November 20, 1948] (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Stewart, James R, no date (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Watson, Richard, no date (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - UNIA Conventions
  - International Convention, 6th (Edelweis Park, Kingston, Jamaica), 1929 [photographer: Shreaves] (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - International Convention (?), (Shaw University, Raleigh, North Carolina), no date (12 photos) (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - UNIA International
  - Dominican Republic: UNIA officials (?), no date [photographer: John Robles] (2 photos) (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Ghana: Independence Day (Accra, Ghana), March 1957 [includes photographs of Vice President Richard Nixon and photo of Kwame Nkrumah] [photographer: Information Services Dept., Accra, Gold Coast] (2 photos) (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Ghana: Queen Elizabeth II visit, 1961 [photographer: Information Services Dept., Accra, Gold Coast] (2 photos) (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - Ghana: Accra visit [possibly Harvey or Sherrill], no date (14 photos) (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - Ghana: Unidentified individual, no date [photographer: Alhaji's Studio, Wenchi] (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - Ghana: Unidentified group, no date [photographer: Frank Dodoo's Studio, Accra] (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - Jamaica: Kingston Division, no date (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - Liberia: Scrapbook of UNIA photographs and reports, 1967 (Box 19, Folder 25)
  - Liberia: Universal African Legion, Annual Inspection and Review (Monrovia, Liberia), August 1976 [includes Universal African Vanguards (juveniles) and Black Cross Nurses in native dress] (7 photos) (Box 19, Folder 26)
  - Liberia: Universal African Legion, Annual Inspection and Review (Monrovia, Liberia), August 1977 (9 photos) (Box 19, Folder 27)
  - Liberia: Marcus Garvey Memorial Institute (Monrovia), graduating class, 1978 (Box 19, Folder 28)
  - Liberia: African Village Cafeteria (Monrovia), no date ["UNIA and ACL first commercial business in Africa] (Box 19, Folder 29)
  - Liberia: Edna M. Kennedy Clinic, UNIA-ACL, Medical Program for Africa, no date (4 photos) (Box 19, Folder 30)
  - Liberia: Liberian troops, no date (Box 19, Folder 31)
  - Liberia: UNIA Metropolitan Division, Executive Officers, no date (Box 19, Folder 32)
  - Liberia: Universal African Legion (Monrovia), no date (Box 19, Folder 33)
  - Other
  - Brewster Housing Project (Detroit, Michigan), circa 1952 [pictured William L. Sherrill, G.B. Bryant, Rev. Henry E. Thurman, and C.C. Williams] [photographer: O.B. Pitts] (Box 19, Folder 34)
  - Garvey Memorial Liberty Hall (Philadelphia, Pennsylvania), no date [photographer: Gaston Devigne] (Box 19, Folder 35)
  - Loring Air Force Base (Limestone, Maine), African American soldiers and base, 1952 (15 photos) (Box 19, Folder 36)
  - Marcus Garvey Institute (Monrovia, Liberia), Graduating Class of 1977 (Box 19, Folder 37)
  - Organization of African Unity, 4th Summit (Kinshasa, Democratic Republic of the Congo), 1967 [includes photograph of Liberian delegation] (3 photos) (Box 19, Folder 38)
  - Groups (Box 19, Folder 39)
  - Individuals (Box 19, Folder 40)
- Writings, Series 4; Boxes 20-21
  The series consists of manuscript and typescript writings by several key UNIA officials including Marcus Garvey, Thomas W. Harvey, and William L. Sherrill; as well as others associated with the UNIA. Writings by Garvey include two notebooks containing speeches (1928-1929) and essays, as well as typescripts of speeches and essays, some which are published in his Philosophy and Opinions. Writings by UNIA Presidents Thomas W. Harvey and William L. Sherrill are mainly essays relating to the work of the UNIA. Sherrill's material also includes typescripts of some of his "We, the Negro," a column he wrote as President of the Afro-American Institute and Federated Fireside Group. Additional "We, the Negro" columns may be found in Series 6: Printed Material.
  Arranged by type of record, then in alphabetical order.
  - Notebooks
  - Notebook I: Garvey, Marcus, speeches, 1928-1929 and essays [not in Garvey's hand] (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Notebook II: Garvey, Marcus, essays, no date [in Garvey's hand] (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Notebook III: Harvey, Thomas W., various essays (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Notebook IV: Harvey, Thomas W., various essays (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Notebook V: Sherrill, William L., [12th Dynasty Egypt, incomplete] (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Manuscripts/Typescripts
  - Agyeman-Dickson, Y.D. (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Anderson, W.D. (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Azikiwe, Nnamdi (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Cayton, Horace (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Cole, Eric S.A. (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Cox, Ernest Sevier (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Daniels, Ronald D. (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Diggs, Charles C. (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Ekwueme, Alex I. (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Garvey, Marcus: Philosophy and Opinions essays, June 19, 1923-March 16, 1924 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Garvey, Marcus: Other (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Grissom, N.H. (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Harper, Frances Ellen Watkins (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Harvey, Thomas W. (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - Harvey, Thomas W., biographical (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - Huggins, Willis N. (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - Kaunda, K.D. (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - Langdon, Henry J. (Box 20, Folder 23)
  - Nkrumah, Kwame (Box 20, Folder 24)
  - Obadele, Imari Abubakari (Box 20, Folder 25)
  - Poems: Various authors (Box 20, Folder 26)
  - Reynolds, Elder M. (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Robinson, E.R. (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Rowan, Carl (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Sanders, W.E. (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Sherrill, William L., biographical (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Sherrill, William L., manuscripts (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Sherrill, William L., speech notes, etc. (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Sherrill, William L., speech notes, etc. (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Sherrill, William L., speech notes, etc. (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Sherrill, William L., typescripts (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Sherrill, William L., "We, The Negro" (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Tobias, Channing H. (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Willis, George (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Unknown authors, manuscripts (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Unknown authors, typescripts (1 of 2) (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Unknown authors, typescripts (2 of 2) (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Unknown author, "Wonderful Ethiopians" (Box 21, Folder 17)
- Printed material, 1928-1989, Series 5; Box 22; OP 1-3
  The series consists of printed materials created by the Universal Negro Improvement Association from 1928-1989. The UNIA material includes broadsides advertising various UNIA sponsored events; brochures relating information about the purpose, programs; and goals of the UNIA; and programs of the UNIA events. Programs relating to the international conferences of the UNIA may be found in Series 2: Administrative Records under Meetings-Parent Body.
  Arranged in alphabetical order by record type.
  - British Postal Orders (containing donations from Ghana and Gold Coast), 1958 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Broadsides, no date (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Broadsides, 1928-1959 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Broadsides, 1960-1969 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Broadsides, 1970-1977 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Broadsides, Oversized, 1924-1953 and no date (Box OP1)
  - Brochure, "African - Every Blackman's Business," by William L. Sherrill, Sr., no date (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Brochure, "Hon. Thomas W. Harvey - Commissioner-Ohio," no date [includes three poems written by Harvey] (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Brochure, "National Public Relations Committee of the NIA Program," Detroit, Michigan, no date (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Brochure, "Negro War Aims," by Lester Taylor, 1943 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Brochure, "New Africa Faces the World," by William L. Sherrill, Sr., no date (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Brochure, "The Rehabilitative Committee of the UNIA and African Communities League," resolution adopted at Philadelphia, August 1, 1943 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Brochure, "The UNIA and African Communities League - What it is and how it operates," no date (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Brochure, "This is our Day," by William L. Sherrill, Sr., no date (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Brochure, "We are not Subversive," no date (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Brochure, "Your Guide to Operation Going Home," [1976] (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Bundles for Africa, various printed (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Business card, Thomas W. Harvey, President General (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - Bylaws book, Black Cross Nurses Division 405 (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - Cards, Marcus Garvey (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - Certificate, The Black Cross Navigation Trading Co., Inc., 1924 (Box OP2)
  - Certificate, Marcus Garvey Institute (Monrovia, Liberia), for Kesselly Joseph, December 13, 1968 (Box 22, Folder 20)
  - Christmas circular letters, Editor of the Garvey Voice, no dates (Box 22, Folder 21)
  - Christmas greetings from High Commissioner in Canada [from unknown publication], no date (Box 22, Folder 22)
  - Contribution cards (Box 22, Folder 23)
  - Credentials of Official Delegate to the Regional Conference (Philadelphia), August 1945 (Box 22, Folder 24)
  - Dues cards (Box 22, Folder 25)
  - Financial book (blank), Black Cross Nurses Division 405 (Box 22, Folder 26)
  - Form, Loan (Box 22, Folder 27)
  - Invitation, Brooklyn Unit, Annual Dance and Floor Show, October 22, 1955 (New York, New York) (Box 22, Folder 28)
  - Invitation, Chicago Isaiah Morter Division, Installation of Officers, January 12, 196 (Box 22, Folder 29)
  - Invitation, Philadelphia Division No. 121, An African Feast, January 1, 1961 (Philadelphia, Pennsylvania) (Box 22, Folder 30)
  - Membership application forms, Harmony Division, Kingston, Jamaica (Box 22, Folder 31)
  - Membership application, Universal African League, 1st Corp Area of the UNIA (New York, New York), no date (Box 22, Folder 32)
  - Membership cards (Box 22, Folder 33)
  - Membership certificates (Box 22, Folder 34)
  - Newsletter: Community News (Raleigh, North Carolina), Vol. II, No 22, June 1973 (Box 22, Folder 35)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1945-1977 (Box 22, Folder 36)
  - Newspaper clippings, Sherrill, William L., "We, the Negro" (Box 22, Folder 37)
  - Newspaper clippings (in scrapbook), UNIA Convention Notes, 1921 (Box 22, Folder 38)
  - Palm card (?), E.S. Robinson, Sr., Secretary-General UNIA (Box 22, Folder 39)
  - Poem, "All Around the World," by Margaret R. Fallon, no date (Box 22, Folder 40)
  - Poem, "Garvey's New Day," by Rubie Blackwell, 1961 (Box 22, Folder 41)
  - Poster, Thomas W. Harvey, born 1893 - died 1978 (Box OP3)
  - Press pass and credential form (Box 22, Folder 42)
  - Press releases (Box 22, Folder 43)
  - Program, Garvey Memorial Hall (Philadelphia, Pennsylvania), dedication, no date (Box 22, Folder 44)
  - Program, Tentative Agenda for Conference of the Rehabilitating Committee to be held at Philadelphia Division 121, August 1-2, 1943 (Box 22, Folder 45)
  - Program, UNIA Welcomes Home its President General The - Hon. William L. Sherrill (Detroit, Michigan), December 19, 1954 (Box 22, Folder 46)
  - Program, The African Land Project (Philadelphia, Pennsylvania), February 2, 1957 (Box 22, Folder 47)
  - Program, [Ghana Independence Celebration] (Philadelphia, Pennsylvania), April 7, 1957 (Box 22, Folder 48)
  - Program, Honoring the Coming of Mr. William L. Sherrill (recently returned from Ghana, Africa) (Toledo, Ohio), May 5, 1957 (Box 22, Folder 49)
  - Program, Re-Interment of the Remains of the Late Marcus Mosiah Garvey, Georgia IV Memorial Park (Kingston, Jamaica), November 15, 1964 (Box 22, Folder 50)
  - Program: Operation Africa, Report from Liberia (Detroit, Michigan), November 24, 1968 (Box 22, Folder 51)
  - Program: 90th Birthday Celebration of the Late Honorable Marcus Garvey (Chicago, Illinois), August 4, 1977 (Box 22, Folder 52)
  - Raffle tickets, Grand Freedom Feast (Detroit, Michigan), June 13, 1953 (Box 22, Folder 53)
  - Receipt book [blank] (Box 22, Folder 54)
  - Song book, New York Vanguard Local 301 (Box 22, Folder 55)
  - Songs (Box 22, Folder 56)
  - Stationery (Box 22, Folder 57)
  - Stationery, William L. Sherrill for Councilman (Detroit, Michigan), no date (Box 22, Folder 58)
  - Ticket, UNIA International Convention (Brooklyn, New York), August 31, 1961 (Box 22, Folder 59)
  - Ticket, Testimonial Dinner (Detroit, Michigan), August 31, 1963 (Box 22, Folder 60)
- Other organizations, 1921-1989, Series 6; Box 23-24; OP 4-8
  The series consists of records and printed materials created by other organizations from 1921-1989 that were collected by or sent to the UNIA. The materials include printed matter such as broadsides, brochures, and programs; minutes, resolutions, and other records. Many of the organizations represented here relate to Marcus Garvey, Black Nationalism, Pan-Africanism, and the Back-to-Africa movement.
  Arranged in alphabetical order.
  - "Abraham Lincoln on the Question of Negro Colonization and Acts of the Congress Authorizing him to Institute his Negro Colonization Program," brochure (distributed by Earnest Sevier Cox, Richmond, Virginia) (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - African American Repatriation Association, agenda, 1969 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - African Continental Art and Cultural Centre (New York, New York), African Voluntary Air Concert, broadside, September 14, 1957 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - The African-Liberation Heritage Association (Philadelphia, Pennsylvania), tickets to "What is Your African Heritage," August 22, 1969 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - African Jazz-Art Society Studios (Harlem, New York), "Naturally '70 - The Original African Coiffure, Fashion Culture Affair Designed to Restore our Racial Pride Standards," event poster, December 13, 1970 (Box OP4)
  - African National Congress (Northern Rhodesia), agenda, December 8-12, 1957 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - African Nationalist Activist Movement (New York, New York), broadside for Garvey Day Eve Festival, August 16, 1970 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - African Nationalist Federated Council (New York, New York), broadside for mass rally, September 14, 1963 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - African Nationalist Federated Council, (New York, New York), press releases (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - African Nationalist Pioneer Movement (Harlem, New York, New York), broadside for Garvey Day Celebration, 1966, 1972, 1975 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - African Nationalist Union, aims and objectives, no date (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - African Nationals in America, flyer, no date (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - African Studies Association of the West Indies, 1972 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - The African Reconstruction Association (New York, New York, New York), membership bank, no date (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Afro-American Advancement Society (Philadelphia, Pennsylvania), brochure, no date (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Afro-American Commission to the Republic of Liberia, charter, no date (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Afro-American Institute and Federated Fireside Groups, records, 1938 (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Afro-American Society, "Who is Who Know Why," no date (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Afro-West Indian Welfare League, "Back to Africa Memorandum Petition, Submitted to her Majesty Queen Elizabeth II and the Parliament of the British Commonwealth of Nations," broadside, April 14, 1961 (Box OP5)
  - All-African People's Revolutionary Party, ideology, no date (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - All African Women's Conference, flyer announcing a send off party for Queen Mother Moore, no date (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - American Colonization Society (Washington, D.C.), brochure, no date (Box 23, Folder 20)
  - American Committee to Keep Biafra Alive (New York, New York), flyers, circa 1968 (Box 23, Folder 21)
  - American Foundation for Negro Affairs, officers, no date (Box 23, Folder 22)
  - Ancient Order of Sphinx of the World (Detroit, Michigan), various, no date (Box 23, Folder 23)
  - Arusha-Konakri Institute (Chicago, Illinois), flyer, 1972 (Box 23, Folder 24)
  - Back to Africa Movement, broadside for Dr. Lewis Henri Micheaux's lectures at Harlem Square, no date (Box 23, Folder 25)
  - Bell, William K., 15 Million Negroes and 15 Billion Dollars, book advertisement (Box 23, Folder 26)
  - Bishop Lewis, "God's Great Mystery Man from New Orleans, La.," broadside for appearance in Philadelphia, no date (Box 23, Folder 27)
  - Black Star Line, Inc., receipt book [blank] (Box 23, Folder 28)
  - Black Star Line, Inc., stock certificate, 1921 (Box 23, Folder 29)
  - Booker T. Washington Trade Association, 9th Annual Exhibit and Show (Detroit, Michigan), ticket, no date (Box 23, Folder 30)
  - Chester, A. Chester, Secretary-Treasurer, Home and Foreign Missionary Department of the African Methodist Episcopal Church (Box 23, Folder 31)
  - Conference in Support of African Liberation, Proposal for Kenya Aid Program, Friendship Baptist Church (New York, New York), April 24, 1954 (Box 23, Folder 32)
  - Conference on the Participation of the Negro in National Defense, Hampton Institute, Report of the Committee on Findings for Military and Navel Defense, November 25-26, 1940 (Box 23, Folder 33)